Reece Thatcher

Junior Full-Stack Web Developer

32 Granita Court, 9
Cross Lane, N8 7GD
07469946738
reecethat@gmail.com
LinkedIn

PERSONAL PROFILE

Full-Stack Junior Web Developer, recently completed a Tech Trainee position with futureproof. I have a Level 5 Diploma, with the Code Institute, in Full-Stack Web Development. Extensive experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, React, Flask, and Django; always following best coding practices to produce clean code. BSc in Physics, where my main project required the use of C++ and Data Analytics to investigate Higgs Boson interactions.

PROJECTS

Trial by Trivia — Code Institute

- A trivia application with a twist. Users can play in single or multiplayer mode, where each question is timed, and users can choose from varying categories and difficulties.
- **JavaScript** is the main language used for the project, the **React** library is also used in the front-end for reuse of components. **Jest** was used for testing.
- The application also retrieves data from the **Trivia API**.
- Deployment of application with **Netlify**.

TwigElites — futureproof

- A locator application, to locate the original Twiglets as they were recently banned.
- With full CRUD functionality, a user can add the location of original Twiglets still being sold, update the locations, delete them, and see a list of all sighted twiglets, once the user is registered..
- The site is designed using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Python languages, Flask framework for the backend, PostgreSQL for the DB and React library for the frontend.
- The **Google Maps API** was also utilized for retrieving location data to store in the backend
- **GitHub** was used for version control and **Netlify** and **Heroku** for deployment...

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Development Diploma Level 5 — *Code Institute*

JULY 2021 - July 2022

- Completed Full-Stack Web Development Diploma.
- Divided into 5 milestone projects, demonstrating the use of **Python**, **JavaScript**, **Jest**, **Flask**, **Materialize**, **Bootstrap** and **JQuery**.
- Achieved a Merit grade for my Full-Stack project.

Physics BSc — Queen Mary University

SEPT 2015 - SEPT 2018

- Simulated particle collisions using C++, during my degree project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

CSS/HTML

Python

GitHub

JavaScript

JQuery

Bootstrap

Sass

Jest

Pytest

Unittest

Django

Flask

React

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Materialize

Wireframing

Version Control (Git)

SOFT SKILLS

Creative Thinking

Logical Thinking

Detail-Oriented

Adaptability

Communication

- Analyzed Higgs Boson Properties and Interactions by comparing the simulations to Real-World Data.

Time-Management

Autodidactic

A-Levels — Battersea Park School

July 2013 - July 2015

A* to A grade in Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics, Further Mathematics, and Business.

EXPERIENCE

Tech Trainee — futureproof, Artillery Row, London

MAY 2015 - NOV 2018

- Worked with JavaScript, Python, React, Django and Flask to build various fullstack projects..
- Worked collaboratively to produce projects using GitHub for version control.
- As part of the project planning process, daily standups were held and figma was used for wireframing and Trello for task delegation.

Client Advisor — SuitSupply, Vigo St.

NOV 2018 - To Date

- Design and fit custom-made suits, based on Client necessity and occasion.
- Identify Client Requirements through appropriate Consultative styling advice and Interpersonal skills.
- Managed personal Client-Base by reaching out to clients, arranging appointments, ordering required materials and sizes.
- Exceeded Sales Targets by maintaining a Sales Per Hour (SPH) of £500.

Mathematics Tutor — Self Employed

JULY 2015 - NOV 2017

- Tutored GCSE level Mathematics students.
- Personalized my students tutelage by analyzing their competency of Mathematics topics and pinpointing the gaps in their knowledge.

Intern — Thames Tideway Tunnels

JULY 2015 - SEPT 2015

- Shadowed Engineers working on the Thames Tideway Tunnel.
- Observed the simulations for the new Thames System to understand and test the Engineering concepts used for the design of the new system.

LANGUAGES

English Native

Japanese Basic - Intermediate

Modern Greek Basic

INTERESTS

Photography

Animation

Illustration

Classic Guitar

Portuguese

Cycling